PName

AWS Solutions Architect/ SysOps Administrator

17@gmail.com

0420

Professional Summary:

AWS Certified Solutions Architect and SysOps Admin, with over 8 years of Systems and Network Administration experience. Worked on building and maintaining servers running Linux, Unix and Windows operating systems on Cloud platform, VMware and Physical Hardware. Currently focused on Architecting, building and managing systems on AWS cloud infrastructure. Hands-on experience with most of the commonly used AWS services, EC2, EBS, EFS, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, ELB, ASG, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, Lambda, CloudFormation, Elastic Beanstalk, Kinesis, SQS, SNS, AWS Config, Systems Manager, Inspector, Trusted Advisor. Proficient with scripting using Shell scripting, Python and Go. Worked in a CI/CD environment implementing DevOps tools, Git, GitHub, Jenkins, Chef, Puppet. Hands-on experience with Docker containers and Container Orchestration using Kubernetes and ECS. Exceptional problem solving skills with good team spirit, hardwork and dedication.

Education:

Master of Science (Engineering)- Louisiana Tech University, Ruston, LA Bachelor of Technology - Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India

Certifications:

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

https://www.certmetrics.com/amazon/public/badge.aspx?i=1&t=c&d=2019-09-19&ci=AWS01063951 AWS Certified Sysops Administrator - Associate

 $\underline{https://www.certmetrics.com/amazon/public/badge.aspx?i=3\&t=c\&d=2019-10-10\&ci=AWS01063951}$

Redhat Certified Systems Admin

CCNA

Experience

Cardlytics

AWS Cloud Administrator, Atlanta, GA

Jan 2017- Present

- Responsible for architecting, designing, implementing and supporting AWS cloud based resources and services.
- Worked on multiple aspects of the architecture, Compute, Storage, Networking, Database, Cost Optimization, High Availability, Security, Logging and Monitoring. DEsigning and implementing solutions on a daily basis.
- Created multiple VPCs with public and private subnets distributed over multiple Availability Zones
- Launched EC2 instances with Linux and Windows Operating systems to support various Web applications and Database.
- Implemented highly available architecture by configuring Elastic Load Balancers (ELB) and Auto Scaling Groups(ASG) for EC2 instances.

- Created NAT gateways for secure internet communication for private instances.and Bastion hosts for secure SSH access.
- Configured Security groups, Network ACLs, Internet gateways and Route Tables for easy and secure communication among AWS resources and Internet.
- Created and managed S3 buckets and configured Life-Cycle policies for effective archiving and cost optimization.
- Setup CloudFront Distribution for static contents stored in S3 buckets.
- Created and managed MySQL RDS database, with performance enhancing read replicas and high availability multi-AZ deployments.
- Created and managed NoSQL DynamoDB tables with scalability using Auto Scaling Group.
- Managed IAM users and groups, created policies and roles providing limited only as needed access to IAM users. Also Configured MFA for all users for security.
- Automated routine tasks using event driven Lambda serverless functions with Python and Cloud Formation Templates.
- Monitored performance of all the AWS resources using CloudWatch on a daily basis and worked to correct any performance issues.
- Worked on deploying microservices on Docker containers and managed the orchestration using Kubernetes.
- Involved in planning to implementing containers on AWS environment using AWS ECS.
- Good understanding of Devops concepts and worked on Jenkins and Puppet to achieve a CI/CD development pipeline.

SC Public Employee Benefit Authority (State of South Carolina) Linux Systems Administrator, Columbia, SC

August 2013- Dec 2016

- Linux administration support for SC Public Employee Benefit Authority integration and data center migration; planning, reconfiguring, reorganizing, executing, and implementation of plan to bring Retirement benefits and Insurance benefits together into one data center.
- Responsible for the design, deployment, installation, configuration and maintenance of Linux-based server environment and software. Completely migrated the redhat servers (version 5.x) from an outside datacenter to the newly established **VMware** environment built in-house.
- Upgraded the migrated servers from RHEL 5.X to 6.1 and later versions.
- Worked with database administrators and successfully migrated database servers running MySQL, Oracle and natural databases.
- Coordinated with network administrators and developers to implement database administration programs and business application programs, perform long-range strategic planning in areas that involve system upgrade, end-user management, and systems programming.
- Implemented system policies and procedures, administered the Linux platform interface with the Internet, **FTP**, **e-mail**, document management system, windows environment,

- storage routines for archiving of data on the system, performed data backups, loaded Linux system releases.
- Installation and configuration of an open source monitoring tool Nagios. Monitor all the Linux servers in the environment and watch out for reboots, low disk spaces and over loads.
- Installation and configuration of **Tivoli Workload Scheduler** for job scheduling on the new Linux servers to be migrated to the in-house datacenter.
- Installed and configured **Splunk** across all the servers and monitored logs, config files, alerts, messages on a daily basis.
- Day-to –day administration and support for the new linux servers post migration.
- Installed and maintained Web Applications, **Apache** and **Tomcat**. Worked on implementation and performance tuning of the applications.
- Configured Active Directory Authentication to the Red Hat Linux servers.
- Familiarized with migration tool, **Platespin**, which was used to sync the servers in the old datacenter, to the servers built in the new environment.
- Installed and configured **Red Hat Satellite 6.0** for package management for the entire linux environment. Implemented configuration management tool **Puppet**, which came integrated with satellite 6.0, on a group of test servers.

Citi Group Jan 2011 – June 2013

Linux/Solaris System Administrator, Irving, TX

- Installed, configured and updated **Solaris 8, 9 and RHEL 4 and 5** systems.
- Designed System Requirements, Designing Storage requirements, Configuration Management/Change control/Release management.
- Worked with Datacentre to get the hardware and network setup.
- Installed Operating systems, **RHEL4**, **5.5**, **5.6**, **Solaris 10** using kickstart, jumpstart and TPM procedures on new servers added to the environment.
- Installed **Veritas Volume Manager 4.0** and configuring Disk Groups, Volume Groups and Logical volumes to manage the storage resources.
- Input physical data centre requirements in Inventory system, backup/monitoring requirements.
- Work servers through installation workflow to meet Service Level Agreements (SLAs)
- Created, Resized and managed online Filesystem for users upon user request using Veritas Volume manager and LVM.
- Patch and Package administration to keep the servers updated with the patches and that implementing packages developed for deployment.
- Installed, upgraded and removed packages according to the requirement using **YUM** and **RPM** package management commands.
- Wrote and implemented scripts to monitor critical issues, as well as daily automation jobs and managing alerts using **Python programming language.**
- Installed and Configured SSH for secured access on Redhat and Solaris Systems.
- Installed, configured various software applications and packages like **Apache 1.3.18**, **WebLogic 7.x. Oracle 9i** etc.
- Implemented **NIS** and **DNS** naming services and administered the public DNS servers.
- Monitored System Activities like CPU, Memory, Disk and Swap space usage to avoid any performance issues.

- Tuned the Kernel parameters for the better performance of applications like Oracle, WebLogic etc.
- Performed backups of Production, DIT and Development servers and applying required patches.
- Setting up cron jobs for the user to deploy scripts on production servers.
- Trouble-shoot day-to-day server related issues and problems in terms of hardware, operating system, applications and network.